<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Christopher Reign DeRenzo]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Christopher Reign DeRenzo]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 18:23:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 18:23:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Autonomous Vehicles: Are You Ready for the New Ride?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The World of Automation in 2018</p>,<p>The following article is an excellent read for those curious about how autonomous vehicle will transform our lives in the next 20 years:</p>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/845de2b598a2e9b5f66e73c48270b46c/noop.jpg?input=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.technologyreview.com%2Fi%2Fimages%2Foptimus-ride-founders.jpg%3Fcx%3D0%26cy%3D46%26cw%3D1080%26ch%3D607%26sw%3D1200"><h1>Autonomous Vehicles: Are You Ready for the New Ride?</h1><p>The self-driving car revolution is about to shift into overdrive. The signs are everywhere. Just look in the back lots of South Boston&apos;s tech corridor, on the streets of Pittsburgh, in the prefab test facilities at the University of Michigan&apos;s Mcity, and throughout a smattering of open highways.</p></article>,<p>The human mind has the ability to consciously process information at a speed limit of approximately 120 bits per second according to two researchers. (https://www.fastcompany.com/3051417/why-its-so-hard-to-pay-attention-explained-by-science) and “the best chess-trained computers can at this point strategize many moves ahead, problem-solving far more deftly than can the best chess-playing humans” as noted on Time.com’s article “Are Computers Already Smarter Than Humans” published in September 29th 2017. (http://time.com/4960778/computers-smarter-than-humans/)</p>,<p>TBC</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/autonomous-vehicles-are-you-ready-for-the-new-ride/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d810c1e8-fd85-4df6-86a5-0e9dc5207203</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 19:45:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquaponic System (personal)(2018)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aquaponic System (personal)(2018)</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a03ee586-8d9f-453c-9943-c44543785e77.jpg">,<p>This project stemmed from the successes of previous projects to create a 99% autonomous eco system for fish and plants with the help of an Arduino for environmental controls.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/aquaponic-system-personal2018/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8d865090-cf51-44f3-b480-92d3fac5fcab</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:05:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineering Club (2015)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Engineering Club (2015)</h1>,<p>Served as president of the SMC DIY Engineers Club from Spring to Fall of 2015</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3a6ca7b5-1a04-46ed-9683-ee161cede2f3.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/engineering-club-2015/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ced0d730-8c88-4ff9-a802-6cee41252a33</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:51:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fan Manager (2015)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fan Manager (2015)</h1>,<p>JavaFX : A custom user interface for monitoring and controlling multiple motors and providing feedback to the UI from various sensors wirelessly</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/215c376eef703d47ab9a4e2d06df6128a1f9ba0a.png">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/javafx-fanmanager/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7a7d6469-6e83-4be7-ba92-54cbb823b881</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:51:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conveyor Type Electro-mechanical system: (2012)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Conveyor Type Electro-mechanical system: (2012)</h1>,<p>Construction of ~11’ x 7’ x 2’ steel structure and installation of automated controls that will communicate with an iOS application (SmartFinder 2011)</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/81e0dce6524d59a03744a16390603609a6e105da.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/prototype-board/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1f209584-44a1-4b7d-b779-7651be8b9c87</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:50:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smart-Finder (2011)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smart-Finder (2011)</h1>,<p>An iOS Application to store information with the help of any/all iOS sensors to identify quantity or communicate with a machine that would retrieve called for inventory.</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/9200d63ee067ef8c1e1b3b156033f9722ab595df.png">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/an-ios-application-to-integrate-with-the-machine/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c7d61ddb-fd16-456b-8f7e-37e5e479b3b7</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:51:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Project Management: (2008 - 2011)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Project Management: (2008 - 2011)</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8b062a90-c027-4ca9-bf6c-1426397ba0df.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/49f1e941-e716-4c11-8ff9-455b05c64cdc.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/project-management/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">20e0745b-98ec-4764-ba62-06e36abab3ea</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 21:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A/V Installations: (1998-2013)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A/V Installations: (1998-2013)</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/431233e4-b070-4cc1-a0e8-392b458066ea.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/080fe441-b875-433b-a175-8a775da66542.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f64a2dba-46e8-4cce-bbac-b1859eae4213.jpg">,<p>This was a converted 1920’s theater which is located in the heart of Mid-town Atlanta. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/av-installations/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e44a6ae4-18fb-4707-aa9c-2a4d09e3bcff</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 18:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e7e52ca2-9676-4788-a32d-1c6b909df0ab.png">,<p>Thoughts about intelligence.</p>,<p>What is the cause of intelligence? The human brain converts and processes stimuli (or input) and stores this information for seemingly intelligent purposes to be recalled later. This effect is otherwise known as intelligence. In comparison, most animals perform in the same manner just like a stray dog that had a bad experience with a human, it will steer clear from all people, even if one is trying to help. Or a salmon and a turtle when remembers or senses where to go to reproduce, then it effectively travels great distances across the ocean to lay their eggs and continue the cycle of life. If we attempt to compare the intelligence of animals to human intellect, all animals currently fall short of human intelligence in some way. So this leads us to another question, What is it then, that separates human intelligence from animals?</p>,<p>The Oxford Dictionary defines Intelligence as: "the ability to acquire and apply knowledge and skills" (Intelligence). Another area of study that might help understand human intelligence is to look at the research and development of artificial intelligence. The definition of Artificial Intelligence or AI, also from The Oxford Dictionary, is: "the theory and development of computer systems able to perform tasks that normally require human intelligence, such as visual perception, speech recognition, decision-making, and translation between languages" (Artificial).</p>,<p>The beginning of all accomplished studies begins with a solid working theory that can be proven through a series of tests and replication procedures. Just as in the study of electricity and gravity, theories were developed about what caused these mysteries and then the effect was replicated in a controlled environment to study the defining variables. This is how a working theory operates best, one before the other, but the one problem we have today in the research about intelligence is that researches have yet to develop a working theory, instead they have tons of data about the brain and no working theory (Hawkins). Without a working theory, tests can not be performed to identify what make us intelligent.</p>,<p>Scientists have developed numerous tests to determine levels of intelligence, but this doesn't identify the root. Another problem with these tests are that they require some form of communication to participate in. So this rules out most biological life forms from taking part in these tests which also prevents us from assessing their intelligence. Perhaps if we understood how the human brain works then we could create a provable theory and then we would be one step closer to identifying the cause of intelligence.</p>,<p>After defining what causes intelligence then we could than replicate this process into a machine and test our theories. After all, computers are very similar to our brains as they process input as the form of information and store it for later use, as well machines can be trained (or programmed) to perform operations more effectively than humans. Since we have created electronic machines capable of communicating this is a great place to start our tests to prove our theories.</p>,<p>Alan Turing (1912-1954) was "widely believed to be the father of computer science and Artificial intelligence" (Alan). He devised a test called "The Turing Test" that is currently used to compare the level of intelligence between computers and humans through a series of questions. To this day not a single machine has passed the test with human-like intelligence. If intelligence begins with a collection or database of knowledge, than Google could potentially fall under the classification of intelligent. The next step is to apply that knowledge to serve a purpose that appears intelligible.</p>,<p>In the Ted Talks video, "How brain science will change computing," Jeff Hawkins describes that neuroscientists have identified a special region of the brain that is shared only by mammals and that humans have the largest ratio of neocortex to primitive brain than any other mammal and this is the cause of our intelligence. Hawkins shares an example, "that we experience the world through a sequence of patterns, and we store them, and we recall them. And when we recall them, we match them up against reality, and [that] we're making predictions all the time." As he gives an example of our neocortex processing information he refers to the following example, "Because you're intelligent and you speak English, you know what word is at the end of this -- (Silence) sentence." Just as this word "sentence" came into mind without reading it yet, Hawkins identified this as the output of our neocortex making predictions and this prediction somehow leads to intelligent behavior."(Ted)</p>,<p>In closing our brains are wired through a newly (neo) evolved part of the brain otherwise know as the neocortex which is only present in mammals. This difference provides humans with far more capacity to learn and apply our experiences to intelligent processes. Computer scientists next step will be to apply this theory to machines not entirely by programming but also by hardware. This will be a new form of hardware similar to a microprocessor and will function like our neocortex only it will perform more efficiently than the most intelligent human when it is completed.</p>,<p>"Alan Turing." Wikipedia.com. Wikimedia Foundation, Incorporated. Web. 01 October 2013.</p>,<p>"Artificial Intelligence." Def. 1. OxfordDictionary.com. Oxford University Press. Web. 17 July 2013.</p>,<p>"Intelligence." Def. 1. OxfordDictionaries.com. Oxford University Press. Web. 01 October 2013.</p>,<p>Ted. "Jeff Hawkins: How brain science will change computing." ted.com. TED Conferences, LLC. Web. 01 October 2013.</p>,<p>Reign (5/2013)</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_reign_derenzo/thoughts-about-intelligence/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4ed716f8-e364-4cd9-a9fc-893f1f2ce1fc</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 18:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>