<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Christopher_DeRenzo]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Christopher_DeRenzo]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_derenzo/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 16:29:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/christopher_derenzo/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 16:29:56 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My First Custom 350 Gal Aquarium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5d281a6d-e0ef-435f-8053-04d552db2ed8.jpg" title="My First Custom 350 Gal Aquarium" alt="with custom A/V install">,<p>South Beach Bistro - Atlanta, GA (2005). This facility was a restaurant by day and a jazz club by evening. The establishment used to be a Piccadilly cafeteria before the lease changed hands and the new owners wanted to offer a sip of jazz into the neighborhood. This was a great learning experience for me professionally which required a custom sized 350-gallon salt water aquarium installed in the entry with a complete audio/ video system for live entertainment. I know some might ask, “what do A/V systems and aquariums have in common?” For me personally these were passions of mine, both saltwater tanks and A/V systems, but I had never built and installed them together in the same place… Professionally it happens to be mechanical engineering that ties these two interests together… From designing, measuring, material selection and constructing for each application there were a number of common tools, materials and vendors. As always there were challenges that charged me physically and mentally to accomplish this task in a small window of time (per the norm)!</p>,<p>I sent my plans to a number of companies in the surrounding area with two major needs: (1) Safety - considering the size and location.</p>,<p>(2) Visibility - as unobstructed by additional support mechanisms that would hinder the view. </p>,<p>Not many companies would take the risk, nor over engineer it, however, persistence paid off when I found one company that understood their product well enough to stand behind their materials and abilities for this application. We worked together during the cutting stage and construction stage then performed the stress tests and verified proper support and sealant around all of the frameless seams. What a beautiful aquarium this turned out to be!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/christopher_derenzo/a-saltwater-ecosystem-inside-of-a-jazz-club/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3b4268e7-e18b-4ad8-8b2e-e35864c171f3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 22:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>